Geyslan Gregório Bem

Juazeiro do Norte, CE, Brazil geyslan@gmail.com

Phone: 55 88 99617 0441 Postal Code: 63034-100

Summary

Graduating in Computer area having expertise in software development, great professional relationship and focused at work. With more than 10 years of experience in development and 5 using basically C and Assembly languages on Linux platform. Looking now for new challenges and opportunities that allow him to learn new technologies and work with new people. With great interest in software development (Assembly, C, Lisp, Shell script), mainly in linux kernel research/development.

As Open Source developer contributed to projects such as Linux, Metasploit, radix, SLAE, uzumaki, xrasengan, C in Fork Book etc.

Education

Universidade Estácio de Sá, Graduating in Computer Programming and System Analysis.

Experience

Open Source Developer

Jan 2013 - Present

Random hacking

Kernel hacking: Linux;

In 2013 started studying the linux kernel, contributing effectively with patches, bug hunting and code improvement.

Tribunal Regional do Trabalho da 7ª Região

Oct 2012 - Present

Judiciary Technician

Government Employee: Manager Assistant;

Analysis of court cases and decisions that depends on the responsibility of how to know to enforce the federal law. And maintenance on computer equipment, as a sport.

Bradesco Bank

Jan 2007 - Jul 2012

Executive Commercial Manager

Bank Executive;

Coordinated 72 bank agencies. Besides the formal banking attributions, developed excel sheets (VBA macros) to automatically track the diary agencies results by email. Before assuming that role, was Administrative Manager in two agencies and Administrative Supervisor.

Diretorium Informática

Feb 2000 - Dec 2003

Software Engineer

Main Technologies: Delphi, Object Pascal, C, Paradox, Firebird, DBMS;

Member of a team responsible for designing and developing three commercial systems:

- * Developed SALE (Sistema de Acompanhamento de Logística e Estoque), a software for control logistics and product stock. The SALE runs in Windows platform and was developed using Delphi with Firebird.
- * Assisted to improve and to correct bugs in SEV (Sistema de Estoque e Vendas), a software for stock and sales control. Runs in Windows and was developed using Delphi with Paradox.
- * Improvement of Lockar, a movie rent system that runs in Windows. Lockar was developed using Delphi with Paradox. It was conceived as a commercial software but was deployed as freeware later.

Other activities involved: Operating system and network administration, Delphi and C development, debugging, profiling, code analysis etc.

Skills Base

Operating System: Linux (Debian, Ubuntu, Arch Linux), Windows NT/XP/Vista/7;

Network: TCP/IP protocol suite, openssh;

Progamming Languages: Assembly, C, Pascal, Shell script, Emacs Lisp, plus some experience in Common Lisp;

Virtualization: VirtualBox and qemu;

Cloud: Owncloud, Apache, MySQL, PHP;

Languages: Fluent in Portuguese, Intermediate in English and Elementary in Japanese (Phonetic Syllabaries);

Open Source Projects

• SLAE: Security Linux Assembly Expert course assignments. All seven assignments accomplished with merit. This project gave birth to some of the smallest (and functional) shellcodes in the world. Smaller than those present in Metasploit. Eg. Tiny Shell Bind TCP and Shell Bind TCP Random Port (latter is unique).

(https://github.com/geyslan/SLAE)

• radix: A kernel project for academic purposes that uses grub and its multiboot support.

(https://github.com/geyslan/radix)

• uzumaki: A simple Emacs buffers cycler that optimize the swapping between open buffers in this famous editor.

(https://github.com/geyslan/uzumaki)

- xrasengan: An xrandr wrapper to make multi-monitor setup easier. (https://github.com/geyslan/xrasengan)
- C in Fork Book: It is a C programming language book project focused in beginners in computers. It is being written in Portuguese but with plans to be translated into English (paused due lack of collaboration).

 (https://github.com/c0defellas/c.in.fork.book)

More Info

- Linkedin: http://www.linkedin.com/in/geyslan
- Github: https://github.com/geyslan
- Personal page: http://geyslan.github.io
- Posts: http://hackingbits.github.io/authors/#geyslan